Guide to the Gerim M. Panarity Papers 1911-1985
University of Chicago Library
Panarity, Gerim M. Papers
1911-1985
7.75 linear feet (13 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
Gerim M. Panarity was an Albanian-American activist, journalist, and longtime editor of Dielli, the first Albanian-American newspaper in the United States. This collection contains correspondence, clippings, diaries, legal documents, manuscripts, photographs, maps and copies of Albanian and Albanian-American newspapers, including Dielli. The Gerim M. Panarity Papers document the Albanian-American community and modern Albanian history and politics.
Information on Use
Access
Open for research
No restrictions
Biographical Note
Gerim (sometimes spelled Qerim) Panarity was the editor of the first Albanian-American newspaper in the United States, Dielli ("The Sun"). Taking on the position in the 1940s, he remained there for nearly 25 years, until his retirement in 1963. Started in 1909 by the Society of Besa-Besen in Boston, Dielli is now the oldest continuously-published Albanian language newspaper in the world. In 1912, the Pan-Albanian Federation of America, Vatra ("The Hearth") was formed, becoming one of the most influential voices in the movement for Albanian independence. Dielli became Vatra’s main organ for fostering Albanian nationalism.
Gerim Panarity was dedicated to the cause of Albanian independence his entire life. As a young man in 1911, Panarity left the United States for Albania, to fight with Memet and Faik Konitza for liberation from the Ottoman Empire. He eventually returned to the United States to complete his education, attending the Hitchcock Free Academy in Brimfield, Massachusetts. He graduated from Clark University in Worcester, Massachusetts in 1926, receiving the Washington Franklin Medal for excellence in history. During World War II, Panarity broadcast through the Voice of America in Albania, encouraging Albanian resistance to the Axis powers. He was also instrumental in post-war efforts to send food, clothing and medicine to the country.
Throughout his life, Panarity published numerous articles and books on the subject of Albania. In 1925, he published an article in Current History entitled, "Albania’s Latest Revolution." He was also chief author of the WPA Federal Writers’ Project book The Albanian Struggle in the Old World and the New. In 1957, he published and edited the collection Albania: The Rock Garden of Southeastern Europe and Other Essays. He published a work on Metropolitan Fan Noli, a prominent Albanian-American leader with whom he was in active partnership through Vatra. He also contributed to such publications as The Globe and The Christian Science Monitor.
Scope Note
This collection contains the correspondence, newspaper clippings, diaries, photographs, legal documents, maps, manuscripts and Albanian/Albanian-American newspapers kept by Gerim Panarity. Most materials relate to the Albanian-American community and modern Albanian history and politics. A significant percentage of the materials in this collection are in Albanian.
Series I contains Panarity's professional and personal correspondence. It also includes secondary correspondence generated through Mr. Panarity's translation work for Albanians in America trying to file legal claims in Albania after World War II.
Series II contains Panarity's writings, both personal (diaries) as well as numerous notes, drafts and manuscripts for articles and books.
Series III contains materials on Albania in the twentieth century, including writings and speeches from Albanian political figures, articles and books, radio transcripts, stamps, paper money, and maps. A small section of materials in Series III are from or about American missionaries to Albania in the 20th century.
Series IV generally contains material about Albanian-American life, its organs and organizations. Included is a small collection of ephemera from the Albanian Orthodox Archdiocese in America and several of their churches in the greater Boston area. This series also contains a set of sheet music from Professor Thomas Nassi, an Albanian-American graduate of the New England Conservatory who developed liturgical music for the Albanian Orthodox Church together with Bishop Fan Noli.
Series V contains images of prominent Albanians and Albanian life, including a number of images produced by the government of Communist Albania in the 1950s and 1960s.
Series VI contains material from Gerim Panarity's life unrelated to his interests in Albania, as well as a collection of obituaries published after his death.
Oversized materials throughout the collection have been removed and placed in Series VII, which also contains a number of early 20th century Albanian nationalist newspapers, maps and Panarity's scrapbook.
While the contents of the collection span nearly the entirety of the 20th century, the majority of the materials fall in the period from the 1940s-1970s.
Related Resources
Related Resources
Browse finding aids by topic.
Subject Headings
Panarity, Gerim M.; Erickson, Charles Telford, 1867-1966; Konitza, Faik; Noli, Fan Stylian, 1882-1965; Albanian Orthodox Church in America; Dielli; Pan-Albanian Federation "Vatra"; Albanian Americans; Albanian Periodicals; Albanians; Albania
INVENTORY
- Series I: Correspondence
  Series I covers the period from 1939-1983. It contains both personal and professional correspondence of Gerim M. Panarity. This series also includes secondary correspondence generated through Panarity's translation work for Albanians in America trying to file legal claims in Albania after World War II.
  - Archer, Martini, Whitcomb, 1943-1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Arza, Agne, Jaeckel, Athanas, Thanas, Tosgai (in Greek), Celay, British Museum, Coty, Demir, Dishmea, Dumaine, Elia, Smith, Fortuna, Fuchs, Kennedy, Kamper, Gardescu, Frazier, Gregory, Esther, Rose, Galary, Lumo, 1952-1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Erickson, Fusonie, 1951-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Gerim Panarity notes, British Museum, Harvard College Library, Vatra, Demo, Boston Public Library, Eisenhower, Furcolo, Harvard Encyclopedia of American Ethnic Groups, Orlov, Florence, Victoria, 1958-1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Grant, Pearson, Speros, Proko, Trayan, Gorski, Flewelling, 1949-1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - H.W. Wilson Company, Fenway Garden Society, Priscilla, 1965-1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Lippmann, Luliam, Liolin, Lockwood, Marku, Massey, Muller, Mili, Moskos, Pappas, Phostole, Prifti, Renard, 1953-1980 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Margolis, Massey, Messinger, Mustafa, Fortuna, Nadji, O'Brien, Petitte, Prifti, Thanas, Trayan, Trayan, Vardamis, Ambrosino, 1957-1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Pano, Johns, Fortuna, Pepi, Fusonie, Erickson, notes, Christmas cards, 1946-1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Tisserant, Noli, Athanas, Albanian Orthodox Archdiocese in America, Cotti, Kennedy, Johns, Fisher, 1957-1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - van Valkenburg, Tite, Roy, Lewis, Thanas, University of Minnesota Immigrant Archives, Terova, Slocum, Newman, Svejda, McKisson, Kirka, 1957-1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Rejection letters, 1958-1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - D. Duma, 1958-1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Stephen Peters, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - University of Copenhagen, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence in Albanian with index, 1939-1973 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence regarding "Albania, the Rock Garden of Southeastern Europe", 1957-1974 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence and grant applications for "Albanian History from the Iron Age to the Space Age", 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Translations of letters, documentation pertaining to legal claims in Albania, 1957-1965 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Partial letter (in Albanian) from Ilia Prenda, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Series II: Writings
  Series II consists of material written by Gerim Panarity from the 1910s to the 1970s. It has been divided into two subseries: Diaries, and Notes and Manuscripts. Subseries 1 - Diaries contains his daily diaries for the period 1936-1959, as well as excerpted diary material prepared by his wife, Sarah Panarity. These diaries cover both the details of Panarity's daily life as well as his observations and political opinions about international developments. Subseries 2 - Notes and Manuscripts contains manuscripts of Panarity's various writings (both published and unpublished), as well as his notebooks, research notes and drafts. The majority of this writing is of article length, dealing with the history and politics of Albania. Published versions of some of these article manuscripts can be found in Series VII.
  - Subseries 1: Diaries
    - Diary, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Diary excerpts, 1936-1940 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Diary, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Diary, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Diary, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Diary, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Diary, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Diary excerpts, 1941, 1942, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Diary, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Diary excerpts, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Diary, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Diary, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Diary excerpts, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Diary, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Diary, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Diary excerpts, 1946, 1947, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Diary, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Diary, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Diary, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Diary excerpts, 1949-1950 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Diary, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Diary, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Diary, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Diary excerpts, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Diary, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Diary excerpts, 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Diary, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Diary, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Diary excerpts, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Diary, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Diary excerpts, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Diary, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Diary excerpts, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 2: Notes and Manuscripts
    - Notebook, 1910s (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Notebooks, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Notebook, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Typed notes on writings on heroic virtue (17th century) and Skanderbeg (1889), 20th century (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Typed notes on Bektashism and Joseph Swire's "King Zog's Albania" n.d. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Notes and writings, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Notes, superseded manuscript pages, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Notes and writings, superseded manuscript pages, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Notes, "Kuprili," n.d. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Notes and articles on Mehmet Ali Pasha, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Notebook, background and bibliographical information for "Albanian History from the Iron Age to the Space Age", ca. 1960s (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Original manuscript, "Part I, Albanian History from the Iron Age to the Space Age", n.d. (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
    - Typescript, "An Albanian History From the Iron Age to the Space Age – Part II," 1979 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Manuscript, "An Albanian History From the Iron Age to the Space Age" n.d. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Manuscript, "Chapter V – Albanian Dress," n.d. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Manuscript, "Chou En Lai’s Albanian Junket," n.d. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Manuscript, "The Origin of the Albanian Renaissance in the United States," n.d. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Manuscript, "Albania’s Chief Enver Hoxha Poised for a New Switch (?)" n.d. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Manuscript, "Albanian Foreign Policy Under Communism," n.d. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Manuscript, "Red China Shares Albanian Beachhead with France," n.d. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Manuscript, "Enver Hoxha - a Maverick with a Purpose," n.d. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Manuscript, "Albania - The Rock Garden of Southeastern Europe," n.d. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Typescripts, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Bound material, "Albania, A Nation in Perpetual Crisis" and "Graphic Story of Albania," 1959 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Manuscript, "Two Giants and a Lilliputian," ca. 1960s (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Manuscript, "Albania Observed its 50th Anniversary in Complete Isolation," ca. 1960s (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Manuscript, "Rollback Policy Resurrected," ca. 1964 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Manuscript, "Albania – Twenty Years Under Communism," 1964 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Manuscript, "Enver Hoxha’s New Albania," 1964 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Manuscript, "The Man Who Rules Albania," 1964 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Manuscript, "Vatra in Changing Times," 1966 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Memorial essay for Dr. Dimetra Tsina Elia, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Manuscript, "A Survey of American Relations with Albania," 1967 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Manuscript, "Albanian Progress in the Decade of the Sixties," 1970 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Manuscript, "Albania – Twenty-Five Years Under Communism," 1970 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Manuscript, "Albania Forges Ahead on Many Fronts," 1970s (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Manuscript, "History of Vatra," 1971 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Typescripts, unidentified author n.d. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Manuscript, "Albanian Emigrants and Albanian Cultures," unidentified author, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Series III: Albania
  Series III contains a variety of materials about Albania in the twentieth century; the bulk of the material falls between 1920 and 1970. It contains writings and speeches by both Albanian democratic nationalists and Albanian communist leaders, as well as analyses of the political situation in Albania. It also includes articles and book excerpts on the topic of Albania. There is a significant quantity of translations of Radio Tirana, the official Albanian radio station, mostly for the year 1960. Also included are a number of Albanian artifacts, such as stamps and paper money from the 1910s-1950s, as well as maps of Albania. Finally, there are materials from and about Americans who undertook missionary work in Albania.
  - Documents in Albanian, ca. 1920s-1960 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - The Fundamental Statute of the Albanian Republic, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Drafts, "Socio-Economic Picture of Albania" by J. Thornton, August 11, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Copy of letter from Faik Konitza to the Editor of the New York Times, September 12, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Faik Konitza, "The Background of the Italian-Greek Conflict," 1940 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Lame Kodra, "Roli I Kulturës në Shqipërinë e Sotme," 1945 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Materials by and about Bishop Fan S. Noli, 1950s-1980s (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - United States Congressional documentation on Albania, 1954-1972 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Constantine A. Demo, "The Albanians in America - The First Arrivals" (in English and Albanian), 1960 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Enver Hoxha, "Speech Delivered at the Festive Meeting Devoted to the 20th Anniversary of the Founding of the Party of Labor of Albania…" November 7, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Nepsi Kerenxhi, "Kujtime nga Lëvizja për Çlirimin Kombëtar," 1962 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Mehmet Shehu, "Speech Addressed to the First Session of the Fifth Legislature of the People's Republic of Albania," 1962 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Report, "The Anglo-Albanian Association" by T. Zavalani, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Manuscript, speech by Mr. Luan Gashi regarding the 50th anniversary of Albanian Declaration of Independence, ca. 1962 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Typescript, "History and the Writer's Imagination" by T. Zanalani, March 20, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Enver Hoxha, "Report on the Role and Tasks of the Democratic Front for the Complete Triumph of Socialism in Albania," 1967 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Essays in Albanian, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Manuscript, "Fustanella Piktoreske," (possible author, Faik Konica) n.d. (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Translation of Albanian National Anthem by V. & J. Newall, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Page from "Scanderbeg," Patrice Colom, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Draft report on Albanian Newspapers by V.L. Misho, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Photocopies from monographs on Albania and the Balkans, 20th century (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Articles on Albania from the New York Times, 1913-1964 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Drejtësia Popullore, No. 5, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Copies of articles from The Black Eagle, 1965-1968 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Monthly Review, Vol. 20, May 1968 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Albania Report, Vol. 3, No. 6 (23), June-July 1973 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - "The Periscope," Newsweek, April 13, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Transcripts, Radio Tirana (in Albanian), 1958-1960 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Partial dust jacket, The Albanian Struggle in the Old World and New, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Photoduplication of cover, The Unwritten Law in Albania by Hasluck, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Catalogs, listings of books on Albania, 1957-1973 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Library catalog cards, Irwin Isenberg’s Ferment in Eastern Europe, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Four stamps from Republic of Albania, ca. 1910s (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Albanian paper money, 1917-1921 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Albanian stamps, 1920s-1930s (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Certificate of Registration and Citizenship (Albanian) for Mehmet Ali, 1925 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Albanian stamps, 1945-1951 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Cover, "Plani i Dylë Pesëveçari R.P.SH. 1956-1960" (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - German-language map of Albania, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Calling cards, Faik Konitza, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Page from an Albanian calendar, December, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Materials relating to Rev. & Mrs. Phinaes Kennedy and the American Mission School in Albania, ca. 1930 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Poem, "Scanderbeg" by Dr. Charles Telford Erickson, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Manuscript, "Scanderbeg, Prince of Croya" by Dr. Charles Telford Erickson, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Manuscript, "My Retreat from Civilization," Dr. Charles Telford Erickson, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Proposed outline of Dr. Charles Telford Erickson's Book, "Life's Little Day," n.d. (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Page from memorial for Dr. Charles Telford Erickson, ca. 1966 (Box 10, Folder 20)
- Series IV: Albanian-American Life
  Series IV contains documentation from several prominent Albanian-American organs and organizations, spanning the 1940s to the 1980s. Represented are Dielli, the longest-running Albanian-language daily in the world; the Pan-Albanian Federation of America (Vatra), and the Albanian Orthodox Church in America. Oversized materials relating to the Orthodox Church can also be found in Series VII, as can numerous copies of Dielli. This series contains a set of sheet music from Professor Thomas Nassi, an Albanian-American graduate of the New England Conservatory who developed liturgical music for the Albanian Orthodox Church together with Bishop Fan Noli.
  - Dielli, December 9, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Certificate, Dielli Golden Anniversary, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - 60th Anniversary of Dielli, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Working copy, Dielli Anniversary Album, ca. 1970s (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Constitution and By-laws of the Pan-Albanian Federation of America (Vatra), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Letter from Vatra regarding its 40th anniversary, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Drafts, statement of progress for Vatra on 50th anniversary, ca. 1962 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Vatra Statement of Receipts and Disbursements, August 1, 1963 to July 31, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Vatra Newsletter, Worcester-Springfield Chapter, Vol. 1, No. 4, August 23, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence from the Free Albania Organization regarding its 40th anniversary, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Announcement of the American Council for Nationalities Service, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - The Albanian-American Orthodox Episcopacy Bulletin, Vol. 1, No. 1, January 27, 1951 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Ephemera, St. Mary's Assumption Albanian Orthodox Church, 1981-1984 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Ephemera, Albanian Orthodox Cathedral of St. George, 1980-1983 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Ephemera, Albanian Orthodox Cathedral of St. George, 1980-1984 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Ephemera, Albanian Orthodox Archdiocese in America, various churches, 1981-1985 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Sheet music by Prof. Thomas Nassi, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Invitation to Gallery Showing for Zoïs A. Shuttie, Albanian-American sculptor, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Advertisement for Albanian Ethnic Night, Cambridge, MA, sponsored by Boston chapter of the Albanian American National Organization (A.A.N.O.), May 1979 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Advertising for show by Lewis Hine, "City Life/City Lights - American Prints and Photographs" at the Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, April 1979 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Series V: Visual Materials
  Series V contains images of Albanian life and prominent Albanians. Of particular note are the series of photographs of life in Communist Albania, provided by the Albanian government in the 1950s and 1960s. These photographs, as well as another set of photographs of a variety of Albanian and Albanian-Amercian subjects, are arranged by subject in folders 26 and 27. Oversized images from this collection have been removed and placed in Series VII.
  - Prints, traditional Albanian costumes, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Printed portrait and biography, Selam Musa, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Printed portraits of Ismail Qemali, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Reproductions of photographs, Faik Konitza and Fan S. Noli, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Reprint, group photograph with girls in Albanian dress, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Reproduction of portraits, Fan Noli, Prenk Bib Doda Pasha and the Abbot of Mirdita, ca. 1914 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Photograph index in French, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Photographs from Albanian government on "Aktualitate nga jeta ne R.P. te Shqiperise," 1960 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Set of photographs with index in Albanian, life in Communist Albania, ca. 1950s (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Photographs of Communist Albania, ca. 1950s-1960s, Politics, Culture, Lifestyle and Architecture Education Agriculture Industry and Manufacturing (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Images, 20th century, Gëzuar Vjetini i Ri, n.d. Birthday party, n.d. Greek choral group, n.d. Postcards, 20th century Reproductions of portraits, 20th century Portraits of Albanians and Albanian-Americans, 20th century Vatra dinner honoring Mr. & Mrs. Qerim M. Panarity (Detroit Branch), March 31,1957 Representatives of the Albanian American National Organization (A.A.N.O.) in front of the Liberty Bell, ca. 1960s Headstone of Faik Konitza, dated 1953 Reprint of Ottoman-era drawing, n.d. Interior of church, n.d. Burgayet Castle where Zogu was born, n.d. Parade, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 27)
- Series VI: Personal & Biographical Materials
  Series VI contains material from Gerim Panarity's life unrelated to his interests in Albania, as well as a collection of obituaries published after his death.
  - Business card, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Transcript, University of California Radio-Television Administration Broadcast 7031, "The Great Greeks," January 26, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Obituaries, 1976-1979 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Lecture outlines, "The Making of the Modern Mind," Division of University Extension, Massachusetts Department of Education, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Information on University of Minnesota Immigrant Archives, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Series VII: Oversized Materials